Anthony F. C. Wallace Papers 1920-2000 Mss.Ms.Coll.64a
American Philosophical Society
- Series II. Research Notes and Drafts, 23 lin. feet (Box 24-73)
  - E. St. Clair, 1978-1999; 9 linear feet
    - Subseries 2. Manuscripts from Other Repositories
      - Historical Society of Schuylkill County, Pa. -- Mining Accidents and Explosions (news clippings), 1887-1889; 3 items
      - Historical Society of Schuylkill County, Pa. -- Miscellaneous (notes and correspondence), 1981-1985; 30 items
      - Historical Society of Schuylkill County, Pa. -- Parry Papers--St. Clair Coal Lands, 1830-1862; 100 items
      - Historical Society of Schuylkill County, Pa. -- Scherr Collection (notes and photocopies), 1844-1856c. 1982; 63 items
      - Historical Society of Schuylkill County, Pa. -- Scherr Collection--Miscellaneous legal manuscripts (HSSC) (includes a 1969 article on coal mining), 1844-1865, 1869; 69 items
      - Historical Society of Schuylkill County, Pa. -- Smith, George (notes), 1860-1862; 3 items
      - Historical Society of Schuylkill County, Pa. -- Snyder Papers (photocopies), 1848-1863; 78 items
      - Historical Society of Schuylkill County, Pa. -- St. Clair Real Estate--Lots sold, 1844-1854; 10 items
      - Insurance Company of North America -- Insurance Company of North America, 1794-1886; 28 items
      - Lafayette College (Easton, Pa.) -- Schuylkill County Coal Mining Community of St. Clair, 1984-1985; 45 items
      - National Archives -- Beadle Ventilation Patent, 1865; 30 items
      - National Archives -- Correspondence, 1979; 2 items
      - Newcomen Society for the Study of the History of Engineering and Technology, London -- Newcomen Society, c. 1983; 10 items
      - Pennsylvania Historical and Museum Commission -- Cameron Papers, 1850-1866; 21 items
      - Pennsylvania State Archives -- Notes, c. 1979; 17 items
      - Pennsylvania State Archives -- Works Progress Administration Anthracite Project, 1985; 10 items
      - Pennsylvania State Library -- Notes, c. 1985; 5 items
      - Pennsylvania State University -- Anthracite Monitor, 1842-1872, 1985; 25 items
      - Pennsylvania. Senate -- Journal, 1855; 7 items
      - Philadelphia, City of -- Carey Wills, n.d.; 8 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- Battin--Coal Processing, Technological Improvements, 1843; 16 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- Correspondence and notes, 1983-1984; 49 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- East Norwegian Township Tax Records, 1869; 17 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- Kaska William Colliery (notes), 1851-1853; 8 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- Kirk and Baum pay list, St. Clair, 1861; 3 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- North American Coal Company and Carey-Cameron Connections, 1843-1866; 33 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- Parry Papers (Historical Society of Schuylkill County), 1788-1870; 201 item
      - Scherr, Robert -- Schuylkill Coal and Improvement Company, 1864; 21 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- Soldiers' Monument, Odd Fellows Cemetery, n.d.; 9 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- St. Clair Borough Council, 1858-1879; 76 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- St. Clair Jury List, 1879; 6 items
      - Scherr, Robert -- St. Clair--Incorporation and Ordinances, 1876; 19 items
      - Schuylkill County Courthouse (Pottsville, Pa.) -- Johns, William--Will, 26 items
      - Schuylkill County Courthouse (Pottsville, Pa.) -- Miscellaneous, 4 items
      - Smithsonian Institution -- Philadelphia and Reading Coal and Iron Papers (notes), 1985; 4 items
      - Swarthmore College -- Bathe Collection (notes), c. 1985; 2 items
      - University of Pennsylvania -- Wetherill Papers (notes and photocopies), 1830-1865; 73 items
    - Subseries 3. Talks
      - American Anthropological Association -- Heroes of the Coal Trade, 1985; 52 items
      - American Anthropological Association -- Plot and the Concept of Culture in Historiography, 1980; 102 items
      - American Anthropological Association -- Plot and the Concept of Culture in Historiography, 1980; 124 items
      - American Anthropological Association -- Speck, Frank Gouldsmith, 1881-1950 (conference), 1988; 32 items
      - American Philosophical Society -- Perception of Risk in Nineteenth Century Mining Operations, 1982; 49 items
      - American Studies Association -- Deciphering Douglas: Or, Why Some Anthropologists are Good to Think (article by Jay Mechling), 1983; 35 items
      - Anthracite Museum Complex (Pa.) -- Miners of St. Clair, 1982; 76 items
      - Anthracite Museum Complex (Pa.) -- Who is Responsible for Coal Mine Safety? The 19th Century Origins of a Moral and Legal Dilemma, 198; 106 items
      - Bryn Mawr College -- Technological Change Seminar, 1986; 6 items
      - Canadian Historical Association -- Ventilation of Coal Mines, 1982; 153 items
      - Drexel University -- Ventilation of Coal Mines and the Perception of Risk, 1983; 47 items
      - Eleutherian Mills Hagley Foundation -- Extended Families and the Role of Women, 1981; 106 items
      - Eleutherian Mills Hagley Foundation -- Historical Archeology Conference, 1985; 2 items
      - Hagley Museum and Library -- Studying a Nineteenth Century Mining Town and its Collieries, 1985; 6 items
      - Henry Francis duPont Winterthur Museum -- Conference, n.d.; 228 items
      - Historical Society of Schuylkill County, Pa. -- Two Paths to Industrialization, 1988; 22 items
      - Indiana University -- Technology, Society, and Disaster, 1979; 39 items
      - Johns Hopkins University -- Circumstance and Dogma: Rationalizing a Coal Town's Experience with a Disaster-Prone Industry, 1987-1988; 77 items
      - Middletown Tricentennial -- Notes, n.d.; 5 items
      - Museum Applied Science Center for Archaeology, 1983; 43 items
      - Pennsylvania Gazette -- Mind of Enoch McGinniss, 1985; 9 items
      - Pennsylvania Historical Association -- St. Clair: An Anthracite Mining Town in the Nineteenth Century, 1984; 19 items
      - Pennsylvania State University -- Circumstance and Dogma: Rationalizing a Coal Town's Experience with a Disaster-Prone Industry, 1987-1988; 77 items
      - Pennsylvania State University -- Two Paths to Industrialization: Rockdale and St. Clair Compared, 1985; 20 items
      - Pennsylvania State University -- Who is Responsible for Coal Mine Safety? The 19th Century Origins of a Moral and Legal Dilemma, 198; 106 items
      - Smith College -- Industrialist as Hero, 1982; 64 items
      - Smithsonian Institution -- Some Implications of Colliery Design in an Anthracite Mining Town, 1985; 15 items
      - Society for Industrial Archeology -- Old Collieries at St. Clair, 1985; 10 items
      - Society for Industrial Archeology -- Symposium on Pennsylvania Industry, 1982; 73 items
      - Society for the History of Technology, 1982; 167 items
      - Three Mile Island Public Health Fund, 1987; 170 items
      - University of Pennsylvania -- Coal as Commodity: Ethnohistory Workshop, 1984; 11 items
      - University of Pennsylvania -- History and Sociology of Science, 1986; 7 items
      - University of Pennsylvania--University Museum -- Circumstance and Dogma: Rationalizing a Coal Town's Experience with a Disaster-Prone Industry, 1987-1988; 77 items
      - University of Pennsylvania--University Museum -- Miscellaneous Talks--Industrialist as Hero/Risk-Taking in Mining, 1982; 164 items
      - Winterthur Museum (See Henry Francis duPont Winterthur Museum)
    - Subseries 4. Miscellaneous
      - Scherr, Robert -- Correspondence and news clippings, 1983-1990; n.d.; 62 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Anthracite Statistics, ca. 1850; 2 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Bibliographic Notes, n.d.; 19 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Burning Mountains, ca. 1981; 12 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Carey Lands (notes and photostats), 1842; 9 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Churches, n.d.; 2 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Coal Mine Accident Casualty Analysis, 1870-1902; 18 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Collieries Analysis, 1845-1875; 30 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Cost Estimates, 1852-1872; 7 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Demographics and Tax List Analysis, 1850-1880; 37 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Diseases (Occupational), n.d.; 3 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Extended Families, 1850-1880; 13 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Genealogies, n.d.; 31 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Maps drawn by Anthony Wallace (essentially blank grids, possibly for eventual maps of St. Clair), n.d.; 2 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- McGrath family, n.d.; 1 item
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Mine Deaths and Injuries, 1869-1885; 59 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Molly Maguire Cases--St. Clair. Includes five selected pages of William M. Thomas murder trial (Report of the Case of the Commonwealth vs. John Kehoe, et al.), 1867-1876; 8 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Orme family, n.d.; 1 item
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Risk and Insurance (mostly brief notes and bibliographic citations), 12 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Society for Industrial Archeology--Anthracite Tour, 1979
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- St. Clair Coal Company--Down Time, 1900-1902; 27 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Tempest family, 13 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Tonnage Figures, 1870-1880; 8 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- United States Census Analyses (St. Clair, Schuylkill County, Pa.), 1850-1870; 39 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- United States Census Analyses (St. Clair, Schuylkill County, Pa.), 1850; 51 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- United States Census Analysis (St. Clair, Schuylkill County, Pa.), 1870; 33 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- United States Census Tallies (St. Clair, Schuylkill County, Pa.), 1850; 61 items
      - Schuylkill County Analyses -- Vent and Milne--Standardization of Mine Accounting (photocopy), 11 items
      - Smyth, H. Gordon, 1979-1980; 23 items
      - St. Clair, Borough of (Schuylkill County, Pa.) -- Saint Clair's Our Town Sesquicentennial Commemorative Book, 1999; 1 vol.
      - St. Clair, Borough of (Schuylkill County, Pa.) -- St. Clair's Our Own Sequicentennial Commemorative Book, 1999; 1 vol.
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Chapter I: Heroes of the Coal Trade, 77 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Chapter II: A Workingman's Town in the Coal Region, 68 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Chapter III: The Coal Mines at St. Clair, 121 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Chapter IV: The Politics of Safety, 61 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Chapter V: The Culture of Violence, 91 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Chapter VI: A State Called Anthracite, 49 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Chapter VII: Notes on Ideology, 35 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Chapter VIII: Economic Rationality, Risk, and the Disaster Mentality, 80 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Corrections, 8 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Draft #1--Cuts, 112 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Edits #1, 192 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Edits #2, 42 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Epilogue: The Burning Mountains, 14 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Preface, 2 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- Prologue--Investing in the Future: The Happiest of Nations, 5 items
      - St. Clair--Manuscript Notes and Drafts -- St. Clair: A Mining Town (outline and notes), 21 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Avondale Mine Disaster--Newspaper articles, 1869; 35 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Burrison, William, 1979-1980; 11 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Clay, Henry (monument), 1985; 2 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Coal region articles--oversize, OS
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Community History (notes, articles, and brochures). Includes grant proposal of William Culver for local history project, 1983; 47 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Consultants and informants (names, addresses, telephone numbers), ca. 1979; 12 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Cornell University Press, 1987-1989; 7 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Correspondence, 1979-1992; 178 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Dexter Prize (articles and correspondence), 1989; 26 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Gowen, Jim (Tom Fox's Philadelphia Inquirer column about Molly Maguires and descendants), 1979; 1 item
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Illustrations: Notes and Correspondence, 1986; 27 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Jennings, Francis, 1918-- (St. Clair correspondence), 1979; 5 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Loose Ends (miscellaneous notes and articles), 1983-1986; 33 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Newspaper articles, 1979-1985; 15 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Notes--St. Clair Area Events, 1833-1877; 52 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Parvin's Slope--Maps, n.d.
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Permissions, 1986; 40 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Personnel (research assistants), 1978--1984; 46 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Publishers, 1978--1987; 42 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Publishers--Alfred A. Knopf, Inc., 1981-1988; 48 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Reviews
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- Revisions, 1985-1986; 31 items
      - St. Clair--Miscellaneous -- St. Clair--Map (by AFCW), n.d.; 6 items
      - United Mine Workers of America -- Historical Programs and Memorials, 1974, 1988; 8 items
      - University of Pennsylvania -- Segal Professorship Accounts, 1984-1987; 130 items
- Series III. Notecards, 1946-1985; 15 linear feet (Box 74-114)
  Index cards with notes on primary and secondary sources for Anthony F.C. Wallace's research on American Indians, Arctic Hysteria (Piblokto), Rockdale, St. Clair, and Indian claims.
  - Culture and Personality Notecards: Box 1--Cultural Epidemiology through Background
  - Culture and Personality Notecards: Box 2--Ecology through Psychic Unity
  - Culture and Personality Notecards: Box 3--Small Groups through Religion, Comparative and Theoretical
  - Culture and Personality Notecards: Box 4--Bastian, Adolph through Evolution
  - Culture and Personality Notecards: Box 5--Applied Anthropology through Anthropology and Public Health
  - Culture and Personality Notecards: Box 6--Ruesch, J. through Rennie, T.A.C.
  - Culture and Personality Notecards: Box 7--Aitken, Barbara through Benedict, Ruth: Vision Biography
  - Indian Research Notecards: Box 1--A-Z file
  - Indian Research Notecards: Box 2--Iroquois and Delaware Claims
  - Indian Research Notecards: Box 3--Ohio Tribes: Adlum-Orr
  - Indian Research Notecards: Box 4--Ohio Tribes: Parker-Pennsylvania Archives; Illinois: General
  - Indian Research Notecards: Box 5--Potawatomi Indians
  - Indian Research Notecards: Box 6--Miami and Ohio, Iowa, Sac and Fox
  - Indian Research Notecards: Box 7--Sac and Fox: Sibley, Ramsay, McCleod and Taliaferro Letter Books through Iowa National Territory
  - Piblokto Notecards -- Piblokto Notecards
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 1--Asia through American Frontier
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 2--American Sects through Xosa, Summary and Analysis
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 3--India (Burma)
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 4--Dobree, 1931 through Abstracts, Specific Movements
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 5--Abel, R.W. through Borneo
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 6--Soga, J.H., Southeastern Bantu through Dimond, 1926
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 7--Early and Medieval through Bibliography
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 8--Analyses and Notes through Flathead
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 9--South America through Christian Origin
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 10--Gros Ventre through Yuma
  - Revitalization Notecards, Box 11--Seminole through Schoolcraft, 1843
  - Rockdale/St. Clair Notecards -- Rockdale and St. Clair Bibliography: Early Local Technology through A-Z St. Clair; includes St. Clair property ownership
  - Rockdale/St. Clair Notecards -- Rockdale and St. Clair Bibliography: Iron through Interviews
  - St. Clair Notecards -- "Workers" (Miners Injured and Killed, A-Z)
  - St. Clair Notecards -- St. Clair Census cards A through L
  - St. Clair Notecards -- St. Clair census cards M through Z
- Series IV. Works by Wallace, ca.1937-1999; 8 linear feet (Box 115-132)
  Manuscripts, reprints, and reviews by Anthony F.C. Wallace. Works range from his earliest childhood writings to published writings.
  - A. Professional
    - Adaptation and Disease, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Administrative Forms of Social Organization, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Administrative Forms of Social Organization, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Agonistic Aggression, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Alfred Irving Hallowell (1892-1974), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - America after 1950: Technology and Identity (unpublished), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - American Indian Land Tenure and Political Organization, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - American Kinship, Review of, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Anthropological Contributions to the Study of Personality, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Anthropological Contributions to the Study of Personality, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Anthropological Perspective on Behavior and Disease, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Anthropological Uses of Historical Documents, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Anthropology (American Annual), 1960; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Anthropology and Folklore (Wallace and Welsh's section of American Studies text edited by Murray G. Murphey and Luther S. Luedtke), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Anthropology and Psychiatry, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Anthropology and Psychopathology (Temple Symposium), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Anthropology, n.d.; 2 items; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Art Analysis, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - As Escolas Nas Sociedades Revolucionarias e Conservadoras (Schools in Revolutionary and Conservative Societies, en Espanol), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Basic Studies, Applied Projects, and Eventual Implementation, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Biocultural Theory of Schizophrenia, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Biocultural Theory of Schizophrenia, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Black Napoleon: The Story of Chaka, the Mad King of the Zulus (notes), ca. 1951; 9 items; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Book Reviews #1, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Book Reviews #2, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Career of William N. Fenton and the Development of Iroquoian Studies 1, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Career of William N. Fenton and the Development of Iroquoian Studies 2, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Career of William N. Fenton and the Development of Iroquoian Studies (Wallace overview in Extending the Rafters: Interdisciplinary Approaches to Iroquoian Studies, edited by Michael K. Foster, Jack Campisi, and Marianne Mithun, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Charles Darwin and the Idea of Progress (incomplete; missing pages), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cognitive Organization, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cognitive Theory, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Comments on Dr. Hammett's Paper "Reactions to Change", 1976; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Comments on Dr. Hammett's Paper (Psychiatric Residency in Service Settings), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Complexity of Cultures: On Being Just Complicated Enough, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Componential Analysis and the Relations of Cultural and Individual Concepts, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Concept of Culture: A Resource Unit in World Cultures, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Concept of Culture, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Conference on Iroquois Research--8th, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Contributions of Cultural Anthropology as Applied to Psychiatry, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Conversion Experience: Talk, American Folklore Society Annual Meeting, 1976; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cornplanter Medal (notes for talk), 1971; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Crossing the Ice: A Migration Legend of the Tuscarora Indians, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Crossing the Ice: A Migration Legend of the Tuscarora Indians, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cultural Approaches to Cognition (Encyclopedia of Social Sciences), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cultural Composition of the Handsome Lake Religion, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cultural Determinants of Response to Hallucinatory Experience, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cultural Determinants of Response to Hallucinatory Experience, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cultural Materialism, Review of, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cultural Revitalization, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cultural Universals in Community Structure, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Culture and Cognition (Science magazine), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Culture and Cognition, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Culture and Personality #1, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Culture and Personality (Biennial Review of Anthropology), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Culture and Personality 2, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Culture and Personality, 2nd edition, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Culture and the Beaver, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Culture and the Beaver, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Cultures of Animals, The (unpublished), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Day at the Office, A, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Day at the Office, A, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Death and Rebirth of the Seneca #1, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Death and Rebirth of the Seneca #2, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Death and Rebirth of the Seneca #3, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Dekanawideh Myth, The, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Detailed Reservations Regarding the Task Force Recommendations, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Determinants of Mental Illness (chapter on Culture Change and Mental Illnessby Wallace; correspondence and chapter descriptions only), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Development of the Handsome Lake Religion (for Handbook of North American Indians), Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Direction of Culture and Personality Studies, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Disruption of the Individual's Identification with the Culture in Disasters and Other Extreme Situations, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Dreams and the Wishes of the Soul, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Dreams and Wishes of the Soul: A Type of Psychoanalytic Theory Among the Seventeenth Century Iroquois, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Driving to Work, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Driving to Work, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Eisely, Loren C.--Symposium (Wallace's discussion of papers by Benson Saler, Richard Emerick, and Jacob Gruber), 1978; Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Emotion Terminology #1, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Emotion Terminology #2, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Emotion Terminology #2, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-
    - Emotional Factor in Political Behavior, Wallace, Anthony F. C., 1923-